Ryan D. McCauley

Software Developer (Full Stack)

Possess not only a wide breadth of experience including full stack web development, machine learning, and Power Automate; but also the soft skills needed to work on teams attained through college athletics and personal business ventures.

WORK EXPERIENCE

HPE, Remote — Software Developer

May 2022 - Current

Produced an application enabling customers to see, manipulate, and analyze code coverage data. Technologies: python, vue.js, and SQL.

J.B. Hunt, Fayetteville AR — *Software Developer*

May 2021 - August 2021

Built a Power Automate flow to automate load board bidding that freed up man hours and significantly increased task efficiency.

Texas A&M University, College Station TX — *Teaching Assistant*

August 2020 - December 2020

Assisted a professor in teaching Python to Freshman engineering students. Hosted office hours and lab hours to teach basic coding and Python concepts.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: C++, Python, TensorFlow, Power Automate, SQL, Cloud (Azure), C#, Haskell, Java, JavaScript, Vue.js, SQL Server, CSS, and HTML

Additional Skills: Accomplished Public Speaker, Strong Leader, and Motivator

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University, College Station — *Computer Science GPA*: 3.65 on a 4.0 scale

ENTREPRENEURSHIP

Castaway Apparel — Former Owner and Operator

July 2021 - November 2021

Built and managed website, sales funnel, and marketing campaigns. Run social media accounts as well as create advertisements.

McCauley Brothers Mowing — Former Owner and Operator

March 2020 - August 2021

Oversaw 30 lawns, managed four employees, ran marketing, and handled all interactions with customers.

2738 Tortuga Verde
San Antonio, Tx 78245
(405) 888-0316
rmccauley01@gmail.com
ryan-mccauley.com

COLLEGE ACTIVITIES

Texas A&M Rugby Club

Engineers Without Borders

Texas A&M Engineering Honors Program

ACHIEVEMENTS

Dean's Honor Roll Spring 2020

Engineering Distinguished Student Award Fall 2020

Dean's Honor Roll Spring 2021

CODING PROJECTS

Coverage Data Analytics Application — *HPE*

May 2022 - Current

Project built from scratch that allows customers to access previously unutilized coverage data. The application provides analytics components that allow users to better comprehend the data as well as tools allowing for the manipulation and exporting of the data.

Business Impact: Directly used by dozens of employees across the Coverage group at HPE, this application will reduce man hours and make testing more efficient.

Skills Improved: Full stack web development, SQL querying, data analysis, and python coding.

More Information: Rmccauley01/CoverageDataAnalyticsApplication (github.com)

Power Automate Manual Process Automation — *JB Hunt*

May 2021 - August 2021

Project where a flow was created to automate a previously manual process by accessing a website, scraping multiple webpages, sending information to a pricing program, then automatically bidding. The flow needed to be general enough to deal with dozens of different company webpages while still being robust enough to gather all the required information.

Business Impact: Allowed for the reduction of man hours across the entire load board bidding space. Reducing the required manual work from 3 hours per day to roughly 15 minutes per employee.

Skills Improved: Power Automate flow creation, front end web development.

Machine Learning Projects — CSCE 421, Texas A&M University

January 2022 – May 2022

CSCE 421 (Machine Learning) covered a wide array of machine learning principles, concepts, research, and tools. The culmination of this learning can be seen in the following four programming assignments which were all completed using a combination of Python and TensorFlow.

Project Assignment 1: Covered supervised learning, perceptron units, gradient descent, and backpropagation.

More Information: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1JnmP44SDN5Yk26tMEBrewRNiW79clFAq?usp=sharing

Project Assignment 2: Covered deterministic state machines, Q-learning, and SARSA

More Information: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1FETfuY9M4wgL6_UaX8kIkMAMINtj82JV?usp=sharing

Project Assignment 3: Covered entropy and decision tree learning.

More Information: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1IPnmOlawCFbfYr8G3sRUUK477Yow73IA?usp=sharing

Project Assignment 4: Covered dimensionality reduction, conditional independence, Naïve Bayes Classifier, and local methods.

More Information: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1NMa_h3E4MdjBJoekagC4qHm-IYyw7vQf?usp=sharing

Power Automate Manual Process Automation — *JB Hunt*

May 2021 - August 2021

Project that created a parser for a language created by Professor Shell called "W" that focuses on allowing users to efficiently write mathematical statements. After parsing it then runs the program in Haskell.

Skills Improved: Haskell, functional programming, and understanding the complexity of code execution.

More Information: Rmccauley01/WParser (github.com)